<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>No Auto-Cutscenes</name>
    <directory>no auto cutscenes</directory>
    <id>2908633985</id>
    <description>[h1]Update: Mega Satan and The Beast unlocks are now supported![/h1]

To get your unlocks/achievements/completion marks, make sure you walk into the chest rather than taking the void portal. Check your completion marks on the pause menu, and make your choice.

Update: If you have Repentogon, you'll get your unlocks/achievements/completion marks immediately without having to walk into the chest.

You can also give yourself the completion marks later on with these console commands (which will also end the game):
[code]
no-auto-cutscenes unlock mega satan
no-auto-cutscenes unlock the beast
[/code]

[hr][/hr]
This mod was inspired by [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2667845009]NO Mega Satan auto cutscene[/url] and [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=938928749]AlwaysVoid[/url]. It can block the cutscenes from automatically playing after Mega Satan and The Beast.

[list]
    [*]Mega Satan
    [list]
        [*]A chest will spawn in the boss room
        [*]A door will spawn allowing you to exit the room
        [*]Optionally, a void portal will also spawn
    [/list]
    [*]The Beast
    [list]
        [*]You'll be taken back to the living room where you fought Dogma
        [*]A chest will spawn
        [*]Optionally, a void portal will also spawn
    [/list]
[/list]

For challenges, trophies will spawn instead of chests.

Mod Config Menu can be used to:
[list]
    [*]block the cutscenes after Mega Satan and/or The Beast
    [*]change the void portal spawning probability
    [*]apply your settings to challenges or not
[/list]

Note: Even if you choose to allow the Mega Satan cutscene, the game may still decide to spawn a chest and void portal instead.</description>
    <version>1.20</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Bosses"/>
    <tag id="Tweaks"/>
</metadata>
